Guide to the Ireland House Oral History Collection AIA.030
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
- S
  - Sullivan, Maureen, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
    Maureen Sullivan (b. Brooklyn, New York, 1943), the daughter of immigrants from Counties Clare and Roscommon, was raised in Brooklyn. She spent her early career teaching and working in the advertising industry. She is the President of Maureen Sullivan Communications and the author of two children's books, Ankle Soup and Custard and Mustard.
  - Sweetman, Ruth, May 15, 2013 (Box 4, Folder 86)
    Ruth Sweetman (b. Palmerstown, Co. Dublin, Ireland, 1942) grew up outside of Dublin and has strong family ties to the struggle for Irish independence in the early 20th century. She is the niece of the Irish patriot, Kevin Barry. One of her most treasured possessions is a bracelet which was presented to her mother and is inscribed, "To Eileen M Barry with esteem from St Ita's Committee New York Aug 1929." She was a guidance counselor at the elite bording school, Clongowes Wood.
- T
  - Tahaney, Sr. Anne and Sr. Margaret, Jan 23, 2013, Feb 7, 2012 (Box 4, Folder 87)
    Sr. Anne Tahaney and Sr. Margaret Tahaney (b. Long Island City, New York, 1931; b. New York, New York, 1929) of the Dominican Order are both children of Irish immigrants. They traveled to Pakistan in 1957 and taught at a Dominican school there while also living and working in the local community.
  - Tatty, Matthew, Mar 7, 2009 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Tanner, Peggy, Nov 24, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    This oral history was digitally recorded on a Marantz PCM660. The interview is approximately 40 minutes long, on 1 CD. The interview took place in Bayville, New Jersey, on November 24, 2008, and the interviewer was Myriam Nyhan.
    Peggy Tanner was born in the Bronx in 1929, but moved with her family back to Kilgarvan, Co. Kerry, Ireland, as a young child during the Depression. Her father, Denis Hegarty, was a commandant in the IRA who fought in the 1916 Easter Rising. Peggy trained as a nurse in England in 1947 and immigrated to America in 1953, where she continued her work in nursing. She became involved in local politics in New York and served on the Advisory Committee on Parks and Landscapes.
  - Taylor, Joe, Jan 29, 2009 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    Joe Taylor was born in 1937 in Co. Leitrim, Ireland. He settled in New York in the early 1960s and became a member of the Leitrim Association of New York, where he served as president from 1994-1996. His daughter Margaret is also in the organization and was president from 2001-2003. Joe worked as a bartender for thirty years at the Liffey Bar in Queens.
    This oral history was digitally recorded on a Marantz PCM660. The interview is approximately 1 hour long, on 1 CD. The interview took place in Elmhurts, New York, on January 29, 2009, and the interviewer was Myriam Nyhan.
  - Tierney, Kenneth, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Thomas, Mary, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Tracey, Patrick, Apr 2, 2012 (Box 4, Folder 88)
    Patrick Tracey (b. Boston, Massachusetts, 1958) is the son of Irish-American parents and can trace his family?s roots to Famine-era Co. Roscommon. He is the author of Stalking Irish Madness: Searching for the Roots of My Family's Schizophrenia.
  - Tubridy, Dan, Dec 2, 2011 (Box 4, Folder 89)
    Dan Tubridy (b. Rockaway, New York, 1948) is the grandchild of Irish immigrants from Counties Kerry and Clare and can trace his family?s Irish lineage back to the eighteenth century. He is the owner of the Bungalow Bar in Far Rockaway, which was featured on Spike TV's Bar Rescue.
  - Tunney, Jay R., Mar 29, 2012 (Box 4, Folder 90)
    Jay R. Tunney (b. New York, New York, 1936) grew up in Stanford, CT, and is the son of Irish-American world heavyweight-boxing champion Gene Tunney. He is the author of The Prizefighter and the Playwright, in which he chronicles his father's relationship with the renowned playwright George Bernard Shaw.
- V
  - Vajrathan-Childers, Monica, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
    Monica Vajrathan-Childers (b. Bangkok, Thailand, 1936) has ancestry from County Cork. She is the daughter of a Thai mother and a father with Irish and Swiss ancestry. Her grandfather was Joseph Culfield James (1860-1925), principal tutor to the Thai Royal Family. After attending university in Bangkok, Paris, and Illinois she worked for the United Nations in Asia and New York. She married Erskine Childers III, the journalist and son of Irish President Erskine Hamilton Childers (1905-1974). In New York they both held positions at the United Nations and developed relationships with key Irish diplomats and civil servants, including Sean MacBride and Garret Fitzgerald. She has contributed to international dialogue on women's rights and also works as a visual artist.
- W
  - Wall, Eamonn, Nov 30, 2011, Apr 4, 2013 (Box 4, Folder 91)
    Eamonn Wall (b. Enniscorthy, Co. Wexford, Ireland, 1955) emigrated to the United States in 1982 and currently lives in St. Louis, Missouri, where he teaches Irish, Irish-American, and British Literature courses at UM ? St. Louis. He has published six collections of poetry and two books, including Writing the Irish West: Ecologies and Traditions and From the Sin-é Café to the Black Hills.
  - Walsh, James, Sep 27, 2013 (Box 4, Folder 92)
    James P. Walsh (b. San Francisco, California, 1937) is the son of Irish parents from Co. Mayo. He is currently Professor Emeritus of History at San Jose State University and lives in San Francisco, California.
  - Waters, Mary, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
    Mary Waters (b. New York, 1927) is the past president of the Cork Association of New York.
  - Waters, Sr. Victor, Apr 8, 2009 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    Sr. Victor Waters was born in Cornamona, Co. Galway, Ireland, in 1904. She immigrated to Chicago in 1925 with her two brothers, one of whom was fleeing the Black and Tans. She entered the order of the Franciscan Sisters in Boston in 1928, and served in Rome for four years during World War II.
    This oral history was digitally recorded on a Marantz PMD660. The interview is approximately 50 minutes long, on 1 CD. The interview took place in Tenafly, New Jersey, on April 8, 2009, and the interviewer was Myriam Nyhan.
  - Weadock, Joe, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - White, Richard, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Richard White (b. Flushing, New York, 1947), the Margaret Byrne Professor of American History at Stanford University, is the past President of the Organization of American Historians and a Pulitzer Prize-nominated author of several books regarding the American West, Native American history and Environmental history. Remembering Ahanagran: A History of Stories is his account of his mother's emigration from County Kerry.
  - Winch, Terry, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
    Terry Winch (b. Bronx, New York, 1960) is a musician and writer. He is the author of five books of poems and two short story collections and has won the Columbia Book Award for The Great Indoors (1995) and the American Book Award for Irish Musicians/American Friends (2007). His experiences of growing up in a Bronx immigrant neighborhood are frequently his subjects. In 1977 he co-founded the traditional Irish music group Celtic Thunder.
- Z
  - Zurell, Eileen, Nov 6, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    Eileen Houlihan Zurrell was born in New York in 1942 and grew up in Woodside, Queens. The daughter of 1920s immigrants from Co. Limerick, Ireland, her father was a member of Limerick Men’s Association in New York. She held a career in administration. Eileen married her husband John in 1970 and began studying the Irish language after giving birth to her son and daughter in the early 1970s.
    Some of the key themes discussed in this interview include: different generations of Irish; 9/11 and loss of life in her parish; the 2008 election of Obama and comparisons with JFK; and her mother preparing the American parcel.
    This oral history was digitally recorded on a Marantz PCM660. The interview is approximately 90 minutes long, on 2 CDs. The interview took place in New York City on November 6, 2008, and the interviewer was Myriam Nyhan.
- Duplicate CDs (Box 4)